<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Vijay&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Vijay&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 15:19:14 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mini project - Weekly work tracker</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/weekly-progress-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 15:19:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/weekly-progress-tracker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So… I finally built something I actually wanted — a Weekly Work Tracker for personal use.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/95407c6c-14c6-40e7-8986-87029d333a6b&#34; /&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been toying with this idea of building software for personal use for quite sometime now, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t gather enough motivation to actually go and execute. Until yesterday. That&amp;rsquo;s when i tried claude.ai—and, oh bwoy, it&amp;rsquo;s freaking amazinggg!!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I vibe coded an entire app in almost a single prompt.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So actually my motivation was to generate a notion template to track my weekly todos (i have recently developed a habit of keeping a paper on my desk and noting a few tasks for the day and knocking them off —needed something similar digitally). But notion AI did a really poor job of realising my dream, so with lots of hope, i then went to chatgpt4, and asked it to materialize my vision. It was disappointing too, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t impressed by the results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crossed 95 wpm for the first time ever!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/crossed-95-wpm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 09:40:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/crossed-95-wpm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So i recently crossed &lt;a href=&#34;tab:https://x.com/pagarevijayy/status/1953101515276914711&#34;&gt;95 wpm typing speed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;here-are-my-3-key-take-aways&#34;&gt;Here are my 3 key take aways:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Backstory, i had hit a typing ceiling around &lt;a href=&#34;tab:https://www.linkedin.com/posts/pagarevijayy_typing-selfmastery-activity-7066450138520518656-22D2&#34;&gt;80 wpm&lt;/a&gt; max speed, with ~60ish wpm average, and wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to progress for multiple months (years).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To overcome it, i had to remove certain mental blocks&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-always-use-the-appropriate-finger-for-the-specific-key&#34;&gt;1. Always, use the appropriate finger for the specific key&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do &lt;a href=&#34;tab:https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Touch_typing&#34;&gt;touch typing&lt;/a&gt;. Earlier I used to suck at typing, and I literally learnt  how to type correctly at &lt;a href=&#34;tab:https://x.com/pagarevijayy/status/1609568896436293632&#34;&gt;~26yo age&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;tab:https://www.typing.com/student/lessons&#34;&gt;typing.com&lt;/a&gt;. I could never go pass beyond 35-40 wpm because the way i was typing was flawed (it was mostly two fingers and occasionally a few others). Learning to use appropriate fingers for specific keys is must if you wanna go beyond 45 i think. And it&amp;rsquo;s never too late to invest in this skill. Comm&amp;rsquo;on we&amp;rsquo;re digital natives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
